ALEX POMA

Senior Software Engineer

+51 973119856

alex.poma.iis@gmail.com

alexpoma.github.io





Being a Data Engineer is one of the things that I am most passionate about, it is a job in which you are never bored, you have to keep studying constantly and always surpassing you, it forces you to be self-taught, and not to settle for what you know. I have been fortunate to cooperate with wonderful teamworks, participating in the different phases of the development of data pipelines. I have been working with data for several years, I also have the ability to work in a team, efficiently solve problems and achieve the productivity goals set by the company and my work group.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Data Engineer

TCS - RIMAC | Nov 2020 - Now

I'm part of the Tribu Data, a member of the AWS Support team, responsible for creating and maintaining different data pipelines using Cloud technologies and SCRUM methodologies.

- Part of the RIMAC Seguros project for the implementation of the BigData ecosystems on AWS.
- Create workflows using AWS Step Function.
- Creation of Python Jobs on AWS Glue for data processing automation.
- Triggers generation in AWS Lambda.
- Scheduling works with AWS CloudWatch.
- Creation of tables and scripts in Athena and Redshift.
- Implementation and optimization of scripts in Presto SQL.
- Logs review, correction and optimization of potential errors.
- Creation and optimization of Dashboards using Power Bl.
- Use of Agile methodologies complemented with Scrum.

AWS | Lambda | Glue | Step Function | CloudWatch | Athena | Redshift | Python | Presto SQL | PowerBI | Power Automate

Business Intelligence Analyst

CMAC Tacna | Jun 2018 - Nov 2020

Inside the Caja Tacna I had the opportunity to learn many things about the financial system, also to being part of the Business Intelligence and Analytical Solutions area, where I was able to generate and optimize Scripts in SQLServer, use ETL tools to create OLAP cubes and the generation of Power BI Dashboards.

- Implementation and administration of the Data Warehouse.
- Generation of credit reports using SSRS.
- Generation of data load packages using SSIS.
- Implementation of OLAP Cubes using SSAS, for the generation of managerial reports.
- Automating the SBS Data Extraction Process using SSIS and R.
- Times reduction for the generation of financial periods, with the implementation of an OLAP Cube.
- Implementation of Dashboards using Power BI.
- Generation and improvement of Scripts in SQL Server.
- Implementation of the Sinergia project that covers the most used and most important reports and management boards for the company's decision making.

SSIS | SSRS | SSAS | PowerBI | MSQL Server | R | DAX | MDX

Technical Assistance - Python and R Developer

UNJBG - H20 | Sep 2020 - Jul 2021

Support the Water Research group of the Jorge Basadre Grohmann National University, generating statistical and machine learning models, using R and Python.

- Multiple statistical graphs were created using R and Python, using the researchers specifications.
- Automate multiple manual processes so allow researchers focus on data analysis.
- Shiny UI with interactive graphics were generated.
- I have created Notebooks in Jupyter and R Markdown.
- A Neural Networks model was developed using TensorFlow for Evapotranspiration prediction.

Python | R | Shiny | Jupyter | Neural Network | Machine Learning

SKILLS

Technical

Python/SQL/R

AWS/GCP

Spark/Airflow

Big Data

Data Pipelines

Machine Learning

Data Visualization

Professional

Effective communication

Teamwork

Problem solver

Good time management

EDUCATION

Eng. in Computer Science and Systems

Jorge Basadre Grohmann National University

2011 - 2015

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)

English (Professional)

Portugués (Professional)

INTERESES

Swimming

Photography

Programming

Cartoons